<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Multicolour - Rest API generator</title>
    <description>Generate a NodeJS REST API for your apps, games and in minutes using Multicolour rest api generator.</description>
    <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 10:02:25 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 10:02:25 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Brief Introduction to REST APIs</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-brief-introduction-to-rest-apis&quot;&gt;A Brief Introduction to REST API’s&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s time to talk about REST APIs. In my previous post, we spoke about Multicolour and focused on what our wonderful API generator can do for you. This time I thought it might be nice to delve a little more into REST API’s to show you what you could potentially be missing out on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve split this post into three sections;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is a REST API?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are REST API’s for?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who’s using them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I’m doing my job right, by the time we’re done you will all see the benefits of RESTful APIs and how their application can streamline and potentially boost your business. There are some big fish out there already making use of REST APIs and reaping the benefits of them even as you’re reading this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-are-rest-apis&quot;&gt;What are REST APIs?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what is a REST API?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A REST API is an application programme interface (API) that uses HTTP requests to GET, PUT, PATCH, POST and DELETE data. A RESTful API—also referred to as a RESTful web service—is based on representational state transfer, an architectural style and approach to communications often used in web services development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://searchcloudstorage.techtarget.com&quot;&gt;http://searchcloudstorage.techtarget.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Straight-forward right? This definition lays out for you what REST API’s are as a bare bones concept, but let’s explore things in a little bit more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Rest API makes use of a specific set of verbs;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GET (This will retrieve a resource.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PUT (Updates or creates a resource.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PATCH (Updates a resource)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;POST (Create a resource)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DELETE (Pretty sure I don’t need to explain this one!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a presumption, when using these verbs, that all calls are stateless. What is meant by this is that nothing can be saved by the REST service between executions. This lack of retention however is not necessarily a bad thing.  In fact, it can be very useful when it comes to building web services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stateless applications can scale more easily to fit load changes and can be redeployed if something goes wrong. The fact that nothing is remembered by the process makes REST APIs perfect for web usage. This is  because it’s much faster and more flexible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the key really and the reason that REST APIs are taking over from traditional procedural design for web based development. They are faster and the flexibility of the stateless approach is infinitely useful when using web based processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-are-they-for&quot;&gt;What are they for?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok what is a REST API for though? Why use it? Well, we’ve covered that a bit in the section above. There are many benefits to using REST APIs for web-based applications. For example they open up channels for communication between the user and the host so that, in a way, they exponentially expand what is already there and what you already have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REST APIs are on the rise and, honestly, it’s only a matter of time before they’re an industry standard, replacing the old guard of procedural technologies. The reason for this is that REST APIs use less bandwidth which makes them more suitable for online and mobile use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re  perfect for mobile apps and games! An API is merely code that allows multiple programmes to manage and transform data in a centralised place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consumers utilise REST the same way we speak to one another. It’s the language of the web. With online resources on the rise, particularly with cloud usage becoming more  widespread, APIs are becoming a way to connect a rising number of people to web services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re building an API, It makes sense to ensure that you utilise the capabilities of REST to allow your users to connect and interact with your online services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is great about REST APIs is that they provide the developer with a lot of flexibility and granularity by breaking down any transaction into a series of resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difficulty lies in their complexity. They are difficult to design from the ground up and it can be quite time consuming! (This is where Multicolour really shines.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a RESTful API generator, Multicolour is ideally suited to bring you up to speed by creating boilerplate code in a matter of seconds! With Multicolour doing the legwork for you, you’re free to enjoy all of that increased flexibility almost straight away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/image_0.png&quot; alt=&quot;image alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;whos-using-them&quot;&gt;Who’s using them?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s all very well telling you that ‘big’ companies are making use of REST APIs but that just sounds ominous and gives you very little useable information.  You may find yourself asking;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What type of companies?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What industries do REST APIs work best in?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will I be able to make use of REST APIs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at who we know is using the humble REST API. Social media websites see a lot of request traffic. The user wants a specific thing at a specific time usually ASAP so  it comes as no surprise that websites such as Facebook, Twitter, Tumblr and** **Linkedin are using RESTful APIs to make this happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think that RESTful APIs can only apply in a social media format though,  then think again. Think how many businesses use the cloud functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wordpress and other blog websites&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Review and opinion websites such as Huffington post and tripadvisor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Online forums&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Localised online resources such as University intranets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list goes on. Mobile applications could also make significant use of RESTful APIs and they do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact REST APIs are essentially universal in their application, from social media to gaming to online shopping! The increase in flexibility and speed that a RESTful API can bring any Web based business are far too good to pass up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you now have a better understanding of just what a REST API is, what they are for and also, who out there is using them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I have convinced you of the virtues of the REST API then you’ll see why Multicolour is such a big deal. Not only is it a peerless time saving tool for development, it’s so easy to use that even a complete novice can have a usable RESTful API within seconds of loading the programme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it works and works well, why use anything else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember If you have any issues using the software, don’t hesitate to contact us directly on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/getmulticolour.&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.getmulticolour.com&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 05:23:51 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/rest-api-introduction</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/rest-api-introduction</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Multipurpose Multicolour</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;multi-purpose-multi-benefit-multicolour&quot;&gt;Multi-purpose, Multi-Benefit Multicolour&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you you’re reading this post then you might be wondering a couple of things. Firstly, What the heck is Multicolour? And secondly, how does Multicolour affect me? Finally you might be asking yourself, Why do I even need Multicolour?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a few minutes to continue reading and we’ll see if we can’t answer some or all of those questions and find out why Multicolour can be the perfect development tool for you and your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-does-multicolour-do&quot;&gt;What does Multicolour do?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those of you who have been following the progression of Multicolour will already be aware that it is a &lt;strong&gt;JSON&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;RESTful API generator&lt;/strong&gt;, a software designed to take literally &lt;strong&gt;MONTHS&lt;/strong&gt; of legwork out of the development process. If you haven’t been following us well, now you know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multicolour functions by creating the boilerplate code for you resulting in a, streamlined and above all &lt;strong&gt;RESTful API&lt;/strong&gt; with which to build your product. As a &lt;strong&gt;REST&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;API generator&lt;/strong&gt;, it’s fast, efficient and customizable and shareable using &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Plugins&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; — which allow you to tailor Multicolour’s processes to suit your specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is essentially the springboard you need to catapult your product/business towards the goals you have in mind. We’ll get more into &lt;strong&gt;REST API’s/ REST API generation&lt;/strong&gt; in a later post and through upcoming videos on our website but for now let’s focus on what Multicolour can do for you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-multicolour&quot;&gt;What is Multicolour?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, Multicolour is a &lt;strong&gt;time saving tool&lt;/strong&gt;. That is the goal. Our endgame. In a world of plenty, where everything and anyone can be reached at the touch of a button, we know that there is one commodity we all still seem to run out of. Time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time is elusive enough in today’s world, without having to spend all day, week in week out, going through the rigmarole of writing the similar &lt;strong&gt;CRUD&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there’s one thing that writing boilerplate code takes from us its time and that’s time we could and should be spending on the business logic and front-end work. The fun stuff. The projects that get you out of bed in the morning. By using Multicolour, the REST API &lt;strong&gt;generator&lt;/strong&gt;, you can literally save hours, days and weeks of development/debugging time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t we all love to leave the yawn-worthy stuff to somebody else? That’s precisely what Multicolour is for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, ok, so how much time can Multicolour save you? We save developers using Multicolour about 90% of the time they would have spent on the jobs Multicolour does for you in seconds. In addition to this, by saving you time, Multicolour &lt;strong&gt;SAVES YOU MONEY&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not spending your time fiddling around with boilerplate code, you can spend it doing proactive things like chasing down more business. Let’s face it, in an industry that values fast, maintainable results, being able to deliver faster will pay dividends in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the Multicolour brand doesn’t just stop at &lt;strong&gt;Rest API generation&lt;/strong&gt;.Once you have your API and you’re ready to rock and roll with your project, you need to know that the boilerplate will be maintained, as Multicolour doesn’t generate any physical code all the maintenance is as simple as keeping your dependencies up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said before, Multicolour is a fully customisable, REST API generator and it gives you the freedom to add game-changing plugins as and when you feel like it. This allows you to streamline your process even more and means that every project will be yours from start to finish. Multicolour strives to be as unobtrusive as possible and doesn’t mess with your business logic so that every project, large or small is unique to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-multicolour-can-do-for-you&quot;&gt;What Multicolour can do for you?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all heard the expression ‘Time is money’ haven’t we? Well, it’s true and whether you’re a freelancer or not deadlines are only ever right around the corner. Rushing to meet a deadline can mean rushing your work and that in turn, can spell disaster for yours or your client’s business. Stress does not breed perfection and in an industry that often demands nothing less, stress is always going to be a big negative factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;here are several key perks to using multicolour that I really think we should address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It’s easy to use, plain and simple enough that even a copywriter with no programming experience was able to create a usable API. So why is this a good thing? Bottom line, it means that almost anybody can use it right away without delay. It means you don’t necessarily need a decade or two of experience to get you started. Basically, it means that you can worry less about the speed-bump that is CRUD, which can’t be a bad thing right?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Top businesses like Facebook, Twitter and other social media websites were some of the earliest web properties to make use of RESTFUL APIs, why? It’s because RESTFUL API’s allow for wonderful things like collaboration, added revenue streams and separation of view logic from server logic. They can allow you to share data more easily and communicate more efficiently with your prospects, allowing for opportunities to add additional revenue streams to your websites.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The speed and ease of use involved in Multicolour means that managing multiple projects at once is now way more achievable. Just create the APIs using Multicolour in a matter of minutes, tweak things the way you want them and then boom, crack on with being an uber- genius.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We’ll be your friend. No, really. We are always interested to hear our client’s stories of success when using Multicolour. Constantly monitored and maintained, our website, the team at Multicolour and even this blog series are there to help you get the most out of Multicolour. Head over to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.getmulticolour.com&quot;&gt;Slack channel&lt;/a&gt; and join in the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next on the agenda for this blog series is to spend some time talking about REST API’s and REST API generation in detail. As Multicolour’s core features are centred on REST API’s, we figured it would make a little bit of sense to give you guys some relevant information and cover such topics as,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a REST API?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a REST API for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who is using them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have given some examples already but if you think that the applications of these bad boys only go as far as social media sites then you are very much mistaken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember If you have any issues using the software, don’t hesitate to contact us directly on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/getmulticolour.&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://slack.getmulticolour.com&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 04:37:51 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/multipurpose-multicolour</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/multipurpose-multicolour</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Branding and voice of Multicolour</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Multicolour is about a year old; as a product, but in real “release” life it’s only 6 months old. What started as a technical solution to a technical problem as my little helper library all those years ago has blossomed into a truly wonderful and expressive tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where I started with the branding and the voice of Multicolour, technically it’s 7 years old and one of my first NodeJS projects and it was a solution in problem space to a usual blocker to mine and many colleagues workflow. I decided I’d build it out, to replace the “temporary” part of it with “permanent”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first version of the product was a big mash of code into one file and lo and behold it worked first time. Was fast, simple and a totally viable product. I had made a generator and that’s where I started with the logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/old-logo.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;The old logo, a modified generator symbol commonly seen in electronic designs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old logo, a modified generator symbol commonly seen in electronic designs. That’s where I started, adding colour that represented the night time dedication I had to building the project out and the fact it was a generator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The logo stayed the same for about a year but now, with the 0.4.0 release of Multicolour it was time for a change that matched the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This logo no longer worked for what was no longer a purely technical solution to a technical problem but rather a simple solution to a complex problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to create a new logo many, many times and failed. What I had in my mind simply couldn’t come out. I wanted to communicate the simple, trustworthy and production ready aspect of Multicolour and with that I created a simple brief, set some cash aside and put the feelers out for a &lt;strong&gt;proper&lt;/strong&gt; designer to do the branding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had an overwhelming response from some of the designers I’ve admired in the industry for years but in the end I decided to go with Dan Edwards at No Divide. I’ve followed No Divide for a couple of years and &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt; loved their work and never heard a bad thing about them. I was like a smitten puppy when I sent the email asking if they’d help me create a vocal brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within 2 weeks, I had seen sketches, experiments, ideas built upon and earlier this week I got the final version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/new-logo.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;it communicates everything I wanted the logo to communicate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;😍 it’s a beauty, it communicates everything I wanted the logo to communicate. It has depth in 2d and 3D space. It works in just about every colour, in just about every place. Just like Multicolour does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the next chapter of Multicolour, an already production ready API generator in use by several companies around the world. With a legitimate logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multicolour 0.4.0 is a massive release for the project. With many new features, bug fixes, performance and security fixes it’s by far the coolest release yet and it makes total sense that it comes with a new logo and new website to reflect the generation of this product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need branding done, I spent 2 weeks constantly thrilled by &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodividestudio.com&quot;&gt;No Divide&lt;/a&gt;’s work and presentation. I can’t recommend them and their work enough ❤️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onto the next chapter of Multicolour,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave Mackintosh ~ Creator of Multicolour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 02:42:51 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/multicolour-branding-voice</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/multicolour-branding-voice</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Write less code, do more. Welcome to the future.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When you’re asked “what do you do each day?” what’s the first thing you think of? Maybe it’s something like “I make web apps” or “I create APIs for apps”. That’s great and it’s a growing market filling with clever people.
What do you really do each day though? You’re probably writing the familiar create, read, update and delete (CRUD) stuff day in, day out to satisfy your client’s needs and wants. That’s cool, it’s age old and it’s your bread and butter.
We all mine through the CRUD to get to the gold; the truly inspirational work in the business logic and the finely tuned front end, the “fun” part of our jobs.
But what if you could get there in minutes instead of days or months? What if you could create a RESTful API with OAuth support for all major platforms, use almost any database technology with full relationship support and JSONAPI compliancy in less than 5 minutes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;enter-multicolour&quot;&gt;Enter Multicolour&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world that’s increasingly relying on automated technologies and the web in general, it’s becoming more and more important to be lean. That doesn’t mean we should cut corners, but that we need to get smarter with what we have. We need to do more with the near infinite number of solutions already out there designed to make our lives easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where Multicolour sits, firmly. It’s not a framework, it’s not a library, but in fact it is just glue between many other open source projects. If there wasn’t a plethora of incredibly clever people out there, Multicolour wouldn’t exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thats-fine-but-what-is-multicolour&quot;&gt;That’s fine, but what is Multicolour?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multicolour is a “generator”; built on NodeJS, it generates various things but right now we’re concentrating on generating functional and super fast REST APIs. It uses JSON schemas to generate the create, read, update and delete operations of your API saving you time and preventing you having to repeat your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At New World Code, we don’t like having to repeat ourselves when tackling problems shared by multiple projects. We’ve always used a simple fake server generator so we can get started with front ends and mobile apps while the backend is being developed but after working this way for some time, we realised that even faster and smarter alternatives exist. Multicolour was conceived to help us create APIs in 90% less time, generating the repeated boilerplate and glue for us in a matter of seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was important that it didn’t stop us doing our normal work though, so we made sure the CRUD comes for free. You can get straight to the project specific logic in just a few minutes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-feature-set-for-beta-is&quot;&gt;The feature set for BETA is:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OAuth support&lt;/strong&gt; for Facebook, GitHub, Google, Instagram, LinkedIn, Twitter, Yahoo, Foursquare, VK, ArcGIS Online, Windows Live, Nest, Phabricator, BitBucket, Dropbox, Reddit, Tumblr and Twitch. With built in role support route and verb based controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Support for &lt;strong&gt;almost any database technology&lt;/strong&gt;, even concurrently. If you have a table; say “projects”, in PostgreSQL and a collection; say “users”, in Mongo, you can relate the two without any code change regardless of the different database technologies or different servers. You can see a list of the supported database technologies here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JSONAPI compliancy&lt;/strong&gt; to prevent the age old argument on how the data should be represented. Have a well written API spec to send to your developers to work from, safe in the knowledge that the API will follow suite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content Negotiation&lt;/strong&gt; was a must. As much as we love JSONAPI at NWC, not all clients can consume it without heaps of work. So if you want straight JSON, ask for application/json but if you want JSONAPI (or any other content type) request it + profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code-less logic&lt;/strong&gt;, if you want to lock those proverbial “projects” in your database to their creator you don’t have to write any business logic to handle that, use Multicolour constraints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self documenting API&lt;/strong&gt; with Swagger and Swagger UI, see your endpoints and even try them right in your browser straight away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a &lt;strong&gt;Plugin system&lt;/strong&gt; that lets you extend and modify Multicolour’s behaviour without limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And many other features but as well as that, we’re building out a new module that can generate a single page, Polymer/React apps to get you rocking and rolling with the front-end as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of these features get in the way of you adding your business logic, all your custom routes and custom logic is written exactly the same as usual in the same place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-i-get-in-onthis&quot;&gt;How do I get in on this?!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multicolour is being very actively developed in plain sight on Github, it’s maturing quickly but it’s still in BETA with enhancements and bug fixes being pushed to the plugins every couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head over to the Github repo and star/subscribe for updates as they happen and if you really want to be ahead of the curve you can sign up for occasional updates and exclusive private beta access to modules by email on our website, https://getmulticolour.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s already in the wild with two companies, it’s powering the amazing design tool Context and the Floato app and backend as well as a couple of exciting other projects we can’t talk about today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have a Gitter channel specifically for Multicolour users to get advice and help straight from the horses mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-next-for-multicolour&quot;&gt;What’s next for Multicolour?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re busy working away on several issues and updates to bring more stability and performance to your APIs so go and star/fork and start work on the interesting solutions for your clients.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 03:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/introducing-multicolour</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/introducing-multicolour</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducing Multicolour</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;introducing-multicolour&quot;&gt;Introducing Multicolour&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multicolour is about a year old; as a product, but in real “release” life it’s only 6 months old. What started as a technical solution to a technical problem as my little helper library all those years ago has blossomed into a truly wonderful and expressive tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where I started with the branding and the voice of Multicolour, technically it’s 7 years old and one of my first NodeJS projects and it was a solution in problem space to a usual blocker to mine and many colleagues workflow. I decided I’d build it out, to replace the “temporary” part of it with “permanent”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first version of the product was a big mash of code into one file and lo and behold it worked first time. Was fast, simple and a totally viable product. I had made a generator and that’s where I started with the logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old logo, a modified generator symbol commonly seen in electronic designs. That’s where I started, adding colour that represented the night time dedication I had to building the project out and the fact it was a generator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The logo stayed the same for about a year but now, with the 0.4.0 release of Multicolour it was time for a change that matched the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This logo no longer worked for what was no longer a purely technical solution to a technical problem but rather a simple solution to a complex problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to create a new logo many, many times and failed. What I had in my mind simply couldn’t come out. I wanted to communicate the simple, trustworthy and production ready aspect of Multicolour and with that I created a &lt;a href=&quot;https://getmulticolour.com/branding-brief&quot;&gt;simple brief&lt;/a&gt;, set some cash aside and put the feelers out for a &lt;strong&gt;proper&lt;/strong&gt; designer to do the branding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had an overwhelming response from some of the designers I’ve admired in the industry for years but in the end I decided to go with Dan Edwards at No Divide. I’ve followed No Divide for a couple of years and &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt; loved their work and never heard a bad thing about them. I was like a smitten puppy when I sent the email asking if they’d help me create a vocal brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within 2 weeks, I had seen sketches, experiments, ideas built upon and earlier this week I got the final version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;😍 it’s a beauty, it communicates everything I wanted the logo to communicate. It has depth in 2d and 3D space. It works in just about every colour, in just about every place. Just like Multicolour does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the next chapter of Multicolour, an already production ready API generator in use by several companies around the world. With a legitimate logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multicolour 0.4.0 is a massive release for the project. With many new features, bug fixes, performance and security fixes it’s by far the coolest release yet and it makes total sense that it comes with a new logo and new website to reflect the generation of this product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need branding done, I spent 2 weeks constantly thrilled by &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodividestudio.com&quot;&gt;No Divide&lt;/a&gt;’s work and presentation. I can’t recommend them and their work enough ❤️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onto the next chapter of Multicolour,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave Mackintosh ~ Creator of Multicolour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 02:42:51 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/introducing-multicolour</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/introducing-multicolour</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
